It's been so long
since we traveled on land.
（ナルト）
久しぶりだなぁ　陸地を行くのは。
（ガイ）いいなぁ！
踏ん張りのきく　この感触。
Solid ground under
our feet feels great.
やはり　俺の熱い血潮には→
No doubt about it,
this hot blood of mine
is bonded to land.
大地がよく馴染む。
（アオバ）
といっても　次の港までですよ。
Well, this is only until
we reach the next harbor.
（ガイ）そこなんだが　雷の国まで
陸路を行くってことに→
About that,
can't we change plans
and go to the Land of
Lightning by land?
変更できんのかな？
駄目でしょうね。　現在我々は
水の国の領域内です。
I doubt it.
We are presently in the territory
of the Land of Water.
（アオバ）大小の島国で成り立っている
水の国は→
The Land of Water is made up
of large and small islands.
So they are not connected
to the Land of Lightning.
もともと　雷の国とは
陸地がつながってないんです。
（ガイ）やっぱり…　船に乗ることを
考えると…　うぅっ！
Well...
Just the thought of
getting on a boat again...
アッハハハ。　じゃあ　雷の国までは
まだ遠いの？
So are we still far away from
the Land of Lightning?
（ヤマト）うん　残り４分の１って
ところかな。
Yes. We have a quarter
of a ways to go.
By the way, I overheard this
back at the harbor,
そういえば　港で小耳に
挟んだのだが…。
偽者が出るらしいな。
but it seems some imposters
may show up.
An imposter?
What kind of imposter?
偽者？　何の偽者だよ？
（バンナ）おうおうおう！
Hey, hey, hey!
I have nothing against you.
おめえたちには
何の恨みもねえが→
Just call it a twist of fate.
ここで会ったが運のツキ。
おめえらの持ってるものは
身ぐるみいただくぜ！
I'm taking everything you own.
誰だ？　お前…。
Who are you?
その額当て…。
That headband?
おうよ！　木ノ葉の里から
暁を追っ払った大忍者…。
That's right!
The great ninja who
kicked the Akatsuki out
of the Hidden Leaf Village!
うずまきナルト様とは
あっ　俺のことよ！
Naruto Uzumaki, that's me!
ヘヘ～！
どうやら　出たようだな。
Seems he just appeared.
え～っ！？　それじゃあ
さっきのニセモンって…。
Then that imposter
you mentioned...
そういうことだ。
（ガイ）これが…　ナルト？
That's right.
He's supposed to be Naruto?
こりゃ　そっくりだ！
どこがだよ！
He's the spitting image of you.
As if!
Hey, hey, hey!
おいおいおい！　俺を無視して
なに騒いでやがる！
How dare you ignore me!
What's so funny?
まったく…　おい！
Damn it!
Hey, if you're Naruto Uzumaki
of the Hidden Leaf,
お前が　木ノ葉の　うずまきナルトなら
俺は　いったい誰なんだよ！？
then who the hell
am I supposed to be?
あっ？　なんだ　おめえ
自分の名前もわかんねえのか？
Don't you know
your own name?
なんで　おめえたちまで
木ノ葉の額当てを…。
How come you have
Hidden Leaf headbands too?
まさか…。
Don't tell me...
俺がほんとの　うずまきナルト！
I'm the real Naruto Uzumaki!
ウソッ！？
ほんとだって！
– No way!
– It's true!
（ヤマト）
しかし　ナルトの偽者が出るなんて→
Imagine that,
an imposter of Naruto.
これも　有名税ってやつですかね。
I guess that's the price
you pay for fame.
で　おめえこそ誰なんだよ？
And... Just who are you?
お　俺は…。
I'm...
《だが　待てよ。　ここでこいつを
やっつければ…》
Hold it now.
If I can beat him here...
ようし　ならば！
All right then.
ここで　俺とおめえ　どっちが
本当の　うずまきナルトか勝負だ！
Let's fight, right here and now,
to see who is the real Naruto!
Quit talking nonsense!
わけわかんねえこと言ってんな！
ナルト～　しっかり戦え。
Naruto, do your best.
負けたら　あっちを本物にするぞ。
（ヤマト／ガイ）うんうん。
If you lose, we'll make him
the real Naruto.
I guess I have no choice.
しようがねえってばよ。
や～っ！
ibitsu na merodll de dekita aisareru beki ikimono da
Made from a distorted melody,
I'm a creature that should be loved
seika wa agerarenakute mo kokoro ga utatte iru kara
Even if I can't better myself,
I'll continue to sing from my heart
dore dake tsuyoi ame koete aisareru beki ikimono ka?
What storms must I overcome
To be a creature who should be loved?
yakusoku ga mamorenakute mo kokoro wa utatte iru kedo
Even if you can't keep your promise
My heart will keep on singing, but...
dono doa nokku shite aketara ii?
Which door should I knock on and open?
aketara doko e mukattara ii?
Once I open it, where should I go?
hitori ja kaerenai kara
I can't go home by myself
dareka o matte ita dake
I was just waiting for someone
kimi ga ima ichiban aitai hito wa dare?
Who is the one you want to meet the most?
kokoro no naka de dake hanaseru hito no kazu wa fuete iku
The number of people that I can only speak to in my heart
keep increasing
dakara tsuyoku naritakatta tada
So I just wanted to be strong
bokura mada yomitarinai monogatari
Our story just hasn't been told enough
muriyari owarenai koto wakattete
We know it's not something we can just quit
dare mo mina jibun no mama
Because we all want to be ourselves
tsuyoku naritakatta kara
We wanted to be strong
Naruto's Imposter
口ほどにもねえな。
You're all talk!
That didn't even count
as a warm-up!
これじゃ
準備運動にもなんねえぜ。
We'll be confiscating what you have.
こいつは没収だ。
But what'll we do with him?
しかし　この男の身柄
どうします？
我々は　急いでいる身ですし。
We're in a hurry.
A guy like him...
こんなやつ　そこらへんに
ぶん投げときゃいいだろ！
Let's just toss him over there.
Are you sure about that?
おい　いいのか？
逃げて　また悪さをしたら→
If he gets away and
starts stirring up trouble again,
your reputation will take a hit.
お前の評判が落ちるぞ。
う～ん…　それもまた迷惑だな。
That is a problem.
Hey wait, wait!
（イギー）お～い！　待った　待った！
で　あんた誰だ？
And who're you?
My name's Iggy and
I've been after this thief.
俺は　この盗賊を追ってきた
イギーってもんだ。
Him?
こいつを？
あぁ。
Yeah.
The only ones brave enough
to stand up to this guy are myself
こいつに立ち向かおうって
勇気のあるやつは　俺か→
まぁ　お前くらいのもんだ。
and probably you.
こいつはな　みんなが恐れる
大盗賊　うずまきナルトってんだ。
This guy is the notorious thief
everyone is afraid of!
Naruto Uzumaki!
No! He is not Naruto Uzumaki!
あ～っ！
こいつは　うずまきナルトじゃねえ！
へ？　なぜそんなことがわかる？
How would you know
a thing like that?
てぇ～っ　だからさ　俺が本物の
うずまきナルトだってばよ。
Because I'm the real
Naruto Uzumaki!
なに？　お前が本物？
What? You're the real one?
Damn it! What a jerk!
Using my name and robbing people!
たく　俺の名前で盗賊やるなんて
ふてぇやろうだぜ。
If you're chasing the thief,
盗賊を追ってるということは
君は　役人なのか？
does that make you
an officer of the law?
まぁ　そんなところよ。
W-Well, I guess you could say that.
Then let's leave
the rest in his hands.
では　あとはこの方に任せて
我々は先を急ぎましょう。
We should be on our way.
うむ　そうしよう。
Sounds good.
けど　兄ちゃん大丈夫か？
あんま強そうに見えねえけど。
Hey buddy, can you manage him?
You don't look that strong.
なにを言ってる。
こう見えても俺は…。
What are you saying?
I may not look it, but...
I am the master ninja Iggy!
忍者マスターのイギー様だぞ。
No kidding? Are you that strong?
へぇ　あんたそんなにすげえのか。
人は見かけによらねえな。
Looks sure can be deceiving.
じゃあ　あとは頼むってばよ。
Well then,
please take care of things here.
Okay, let's go!
では　いきましょう。
Damn it.
ったく。
すまねえ　相棒。
Sorry, partner.
はぁん？　バカヤロー！
てめえがやられてどうすんだよ。
You idiot!
What if you were killed?
Are you stupid?
このウスノロが！
俺もやっつける
つもりだったんだよ。
I was going to beat him up.
But you heard, didn't you?
でも聞いたろ？　あいつは
本物のうずまきナルトだったんだぜ。
He was the real Naruto Uzumaki.
まぁ　まさかこんなところで本物に
会うとは思わなかったけどよ。
Yeah. Of all places,
I never expected to encounter
the real guy here.
って　バカヤローが。　バンナ　てめえの
言い訳なんざどうでもいい。
You idiot! That's enough
of your excuses, Banna!
俺たちの計画は　暴れるてめえを
俺がやっつけて名前を売る。
According to our plan,
you're the troublemaker
and I'm going to beat you up
and build up my reputation.
これから始まる戦争に
そのくらいの手柄がなきゃ→
War's about to break out.
I have to do something like this
to build myself up!
高く売り込めねえ。
うずまきナルトをやっつければ→
By beating Naruto Uzumaki,
I'll make a name for myself!
俺の名前が評判になるんだよ。
俺だってわかってるよ。
I know that.
But isn't it time we stopped
dangerous stuff like this?
でもよ　もうこんな危ねえこと
やめねえか？
てめえ
俺からの恩を忘れたのかよ。
You jerk!
Did you forget what you owe me?
俺がいなかったら今ごろ　てめえは
まだ一人ぼっちで泣いていた。
If it weren't for me,
you'd still be all alone,
crying your eyes out.
Isn't that right?
そうだろうが。
ごめんよ。
I-I'm sorry.
イギーは俺にとって
たった１人の友達だからよ。
Iggy, you're my one and only friend.
けど　今度は俺たちでも
倒せそうな弱いやつらを…。
Next time, let's find someone weaker
that even we can beat.
Why you!
このっ！
俺たちでも倒せるだと？
俺の手にかかりゃ→
"That even we can beat"?!
A Naruto Uzumaki or two would
be a piece of cake for me!
うずまきナルトの１人や２人くらい
どうってことねえんだよ。
許してくれよ　イギー。
Forgive me, Iggy.
As long as you understand,
it's okay.
わかりゃいいんだ。　わかりゃ。
Is it true that Naruto Uzumaki is
robbing people in these parts?
この辺りで　うずまきナルトが
盗賊をやっているというのは→
本当なのか？
ああ　間違いない。
Yeah, no doubt about it.
もう何人も被害にあっている。
There have been
a number of victims.
He's supposedly a giant
with a reddish face.
なんでも　赤ら顔の巨漢だそうだ。
しかし　なぜ
うずまきナルトがここで盗賊など？
But why would Naruto Uzumaki
stoop to robbery here?
やつは里を救った
英雄ではないのか？
Isn't he a hero who saved
his village?
詳細はわからぬが　うずまきナルトは
里の厄介者だった→
I don't know the details,
but there are also rumors
that Naruto Uzumaki was
considered a nuisance.
との噂もあるからな。
抜け忍になったのかもしれぬ。
Maybe he became a Rogue Ninja?
里を抜けたのなら
木ノ葉も追っているはず。
If he's a deserter,
then the Hidden Leaf
must be after him too.
捕まえれば　木ノ葉は
受け渡し金として大金を払う。
If we capture him,
the Hidden Leaf will
pay us handsomely.
だが　大丈夫か？
相手は　うずまきナルトだぞ。
But can we do it?
After all, he's Naruto Uzumaki.
臆するな。　うずまきナルトは中忍試験
にも受かってはいないと聞く。
Don't panic.
From what I hear,
Naruto Uzumaki didn't even
pass the Chunin Exam.
英雄伝説はおそらくでっち上げだ。
なるほどな。
The legend of him being a hero
is probably a big exaggeration.
I get it.
俺たち傭兵忍者にとっちゃ
やつはカネのなる木というわけか。
For Mercenary Ninja like us,
he means money, right?
そのとおりだ。
Exactly.
まあ　俺の強さをもってすりゃあ→
Well, considering my strength,
本当は　こんなことする必要は
ねえんだけどよ。
I actually don't need to
resort to this stuff.
寄ってらっしゃい
見てらっしゃい！
Come one, come all!
世のため人のため
世界の平和を守る大忍者→
I preserve the peace for
the people and the world!
イギー様たぁ　俺のことよ！
The great Iggy, that's me!
イギー　かっこいい！
イギーは本気出したら強えもんな。
You're so cool, Iggy!
When you're serious,
you're really strong, Iggy!
すぐにでも戦争で活躍できるぜ。
You could fight in the war anytime!
あたぼうよ！
Damned right I can!
俺は　畑仕事なんかやめて
英雄になる。
Forget farming.
I'm going to be a war hero!
ほら　つけな。
Here, put this on.
これで　お前はまた
うずまきナルトだ。
Then you'll be
Naruto Uzumaki again.
（イギー）おっ　見ろよバンナ…
じゃなくて　ナルト。
Hey look, Banna...
I mean, Naruto.
獲物が来たぜ。
Here come our victims.
行商なら
お前が負けることもねえだろ。
There's no way you can lose
to peddlers like them.
Nope.
うん。　よし　行ってくるぜ！
All right! Here I go!
ん？
おう　おう　おう！
Hey, hey, hey!
I have nothing against you.
おめえたちには縁も恨みもねえが
ここで会ったが運の尽き。
Just call it a twist of fate.
おめえらの持ってるものは
この　うずまきナルトが→
I, Naruto Uzumaki,
will be taking all your belongings.
身ぐるみいただくぜ！
うずまきナルトって言ったか？
Did you say Naruto Uzumaki?
あ　そうそう
おとなしく置いてけば…。
Uh yeah... that's right.
So just put everything down and leave.
あ…。
な　何だ？
W-What the hell?
あいつら　行商じゃねえのかよ。
Aren't they peddlers?
これは　ちょうどいいぜ。
うずまきナルトか。
This is perfect!
Naruto Uzumaki, eh?
そっちから
やってきてくれるとはな。
Imagine, you coming to us.
W-What'd you say?
何？　な　何！？
捕らえろ！
Capture him!
ウソ！？
No way!
うぅ…。
うっ…　うわぁ！
待ってくれ！
こいつは　うずまきナルトじゃねえ。
W-Wait! He's not Naruto Uzumaki!
バンナって　チンケな盗賊だ。
He's just a petty thief named Banna.
なんだと！？
だが　こいつの外見は噂どおり。
What?
But he looks just like
how rumors describe him.
And he's wearing
a Hidden Leaf headband.
それに木ノ葉の額当てもしている。
いや　それは　俺が…。
Well, that's because I...
貴様は誰だ？　こいつの仲間か？
Who are you?
Are you his partner?
邪魔をするなら
貴様も始末してやろうか？
Interfere and we'll get rid of you too.
え…　そんな…。
No, I...
違う！　俺は　うずまきナルトだ。
そいつは俺の仲間じゃねえ。
He's wrong!
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
He's not my partner!
山奥の村から来た農家の出さ。
He's just a low-class farmer
from a mountain village!
畑仕事が嫌で
忍者の真似事をやってやがる。
He hates working the fields,
so he pretends to be a ninja!
俺を捕まえれば
名前が売れると思って→
He thinks my capture will
be his ticket to fame!
つきまとってるのさ！
《バンナ…》
That's why he's hanging around!
Banna...
チッ　エセ忍者かよ。
Sheesh, a ninja wannabe.
ならば引っ込んでいてもらおうか。
でなければ始末するぞ。
Well then, stay out of the way.
Or we'll take care of you too!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
《どうしたら…　どうしたら…》
What do I do?
What do I do?!
ふぅ～
やっと腹の虫がおさまった。
Finally, I'm not hungry anymore!
ハハハ。
では先を急ぐぞ。
Well, we'd better hurry.
Wait, wait, wait!
（イギー）待て待て待て　待ってくれ！
Please wait up!
よかった　見つかった。
Thank goodness I found you.
どうしたんだよ？
それが　申し訳ねえが→
What's the matter?
Well, I hate to say this,
お前たちから預かった盗賊を
別の盗賊に奪われた。
but some other thieves took
the thief you left in my custody.
なんだって！？
それで　頼みがある。
What?!
I have to ask you a favor.
Please get that thief back.
あの盗賊を
奪い返してもらいてえんだ。
けど　あんた忍者マスターなんだろ？
自分でやりゃいいじゃねえかよ。
I thought you were a master ninja.
Can't you get him back yourself?
い　いや…　それがちょっと
今の俺は本調子じゃねえ。
A-Actually, I'm out of shape right now.
忍者に調子もクソもあるのか？
A ninja's always supposed
to be in shape.
悪いが
我々には急ぎの用事があるんだ。
Sorry, but we have
urgent business to attend to.
それに　君は役人なんだろ？
だったら役所へ戻り→
And besides, aren't you
an officer of the law?
Why don't you go back
to your headquarters
助けを呼んだらどうだ？　な！
いや　それは…。
and get backup?
Well, that's...
それに盗賊が盗賊に盗まれようと
しょせん同じ穴の狢。
So the thieves catch a thief.
I'd say they're birds of a feather.
自業自得ってやつだな。
いや　ちょっと待ってくれ！
You reap what you sow.
No, it's not like that!
やつは悪党でも
そんなに悪いやつではなかった。
He may've done wrong,
but he really wasn't that bad.
え？
Because of his looks and size,
people didn't like him.
あいつは…
あんな見てくれのせいで→
みんなには嫌われ
恐れられてきたが→
They were scared of him.
昔から気弱で　お人好しで
人の面倒見はいいやつだし…。
He was always such
a weakling and kind-hearted.
He's good at taking care of people.
ずいぶんと
あいつのこと詳しいんだな。
You sure know a lot about him.
それは…。
Well...
そもそも君は
本当に役人なのかな？
Are you really an officer?
最初から
様子がおかしいとは思ってたんだ。
I had my suspicions about you
from the very beginning.
わかった　正直に話す…　何もかも。
All right. I'll be honest with you.
I'll tell you everything.
これがすべてだ。
何だよ　そりゃあ！？
And that's it.
What were you doing?
どうして　そんなバカなことを！？
頼む　助けてくれ！
How could you think of
something so stupid?
Please help me!
あんた　木ノ葉の里を救った
英雄なんだろ！？
You're the hero who saved
the Hidden Leaf Village, right?
おい　友達だったら　どうして
そんなことさせたんだよ？
Hey, if you were his friend,
how could you let him
do such a thing?
友達だったら
どうして　あいつのこと→
If you were his friend,
why didn't you seriously think
about his well-being?!
もっと
考えてやらなかったんだよ！
友達？　何　言ってんだ！
Friend?
G-Give me a break.
He's not a friend.
別に
あいつは友達なんかじゃねえ。
あいつはバカだから　都合がいいから
一緒にいただけで→
He's stupid.
It was just convenient.
That's why we stayed together.
別に友達なんかじゃねえ。
He's not a friend.
友達じゃねえ…　だと！？
"Not a friend"?
何しやがんだよ！
What's the big idea?!
じゃあ　お前にとって
あいつは何なんだよ！？
Then just what is he to you?!
確かに　おめえは→
You might have come this far
thinking he was just an idiot.
あいつをバカにしながら
生きてきたのかもしれねえ。
でも…　あいつと　お前は→
But haven't you two been
together since you were kids?
ずっと
小さい頃から一緒にいたんだろ！？
すっと一緒に生きてきたんだろ！？
You've survived together!
それは友達じゃねえのかよ！
Wouldn't you consider
that being friends?!
ナルト！
Naruto.
これは命令だ。
わかったよ。
This is an order.
Okay, I got it.
時間があれば
君の頼みを聞いてやりたい。
If we had time,
we would want to help you.
But that's just not possible right now.
だが　今は無理だ。
え？
今の我々は　迂闊に
正体と居所を知られるような→
Right now, we cannot afford to have
our identities and
whereabouts known.
悶着は起こしたくない。
君も我々に会ったことは
忘れてくれ。
You must forget
you met us here too.
行きましょう！
あ…。
Let's go!
待ってくれ！
頼む　俺１人じゃ無理だ！
Wait!
Please! I can't do it by myself!
聞いただろ？
手は貸せねえんだよ。
You heard us.
We can't help you.
そんな…
だったら俺は　どうすればいい？
That's...
Then what am I supposed to do?
自分のことは…
自分で考えるんだな。
It's your problem.
You figure it out yourself.
あいつが…　友達？
He's my friend?
♪～
起爆札！？
何やつ！？
Paper Bombs!
Who is it?!
イギー！？　どうして…。
Iggy? Why are you doing this?
やはり　お前…。
こいつの仲間か！
You... I knew it.
You're his partner?
仲間なんかじゃねえ。
友達でもねえ。
I'm not his partner.
He's not my friend either.
こいつは…　俺の親友だ！！
He's...
my best friend!
イギー！
Iggy...
（２人）うわっ！
おのれ！　しまった！
逃げやがった。
Why you!
Damn it!
They got away!
追え！
After them!
バンナ　大丈夫か？
どうして？
Banna, are you all right?
Why?
ったく　この役立たずが！
お前を救わなくちゃ→
Damn it! You're hopeless!
If I didn't save you,
what'll happen to our next strategy?
俺たちの作戦は
次ができねえだろ。
イギー。
Iggy...
俺は　ずっと
お前を利用してたんだ。
All these years,
I've done nothing but use you.
んなことはねえ。
That isn't true. Everyone hated me
and looked at me
俺は　鬼みてえな見てくれで
みんなに嫌われてた。
like I was the devil himself.
でも　イギーは友達になってくれた。
（イギー）バカ野郎。
But you became my friend.
You idiot.
それは　あのとき
俺も他のやつにいじめられてて→
Back then, the others bullied me too.
お前をからかえば
俺をいじめないって言われて…。
They told me that if I teased you,
they wouldn't bully me.
知ってるよ。
でも　イギーは親友になってくれた。
I know that. But...
Iggy, you became my best friend!
出てこい　うずまきナルト！
もう逃がさねえぞ！
Come on out, Naruto Uzumaki!
We won't let you get away again.
見せてやろうぜ
俺たちの最後の意地を！
Let's show them
our willpower once last time!
あぁ　俺は　どこまでも
イギーに　ついていくぜ！
Yeah!
Wherever you go,
I'll follow you, Iggy!
いくぜ！
おぉ！
Let's do it!
Right!
うぅ！
へなちょこが。
You novice.
そんな腕で
俺たちに勝てると思うてか？
You think you can beat us
with that skill level?
うずまきナルトは生け捕りだ。
もう１人は殺せ！
Take Naruto Uzumaki alive!
Kill the other one.
ごめんな。
俺が　ナルトみてえに強かったら→
I'm sorry.
If I were strong like Naruto,
I could've protected you.
イギーを守れたのに…。
バンナ…。
Banna...
逃げろ！
バンナ！
Run!
Banna!
ありがとう
俺を親友って言ってくれて…。
Thanks for calling me
your best friend.
死ね！
（イギー）バンナ！
Die!
Banna!
なに！？
What?!
ったく　てめえら　見てらんねえぜ。
Damn it.
You two are something else!
あ…。
お　お前たち…。
Y-You guys...
やあ　すまなかったな。
Sorry, but we didn't
believe you back there.
あのときの君の話だけでは
信用できなかったんでな。
それで　君を試させてもらった。
（イギー）俺を？
So we decided to test you.
Test me?
俺は今　猛烈に感動している！
Right now, I am totally moved!
よくぞ友を見捨てなかった！
よくぞ　友情を信じた！
You didn't abandon your friend!
You put your faith in friendship!
おうおうおう！　ここにいるお方を
どなたと心得る！？
Hey, hey, hey!
Just who do you think
this person is?
こちらに　おわすお方は
木ノ葉の里を守った英雄→
This here is the hero who
saved Hidden Leaf Village,
うずまきナルト様であるぞ！
（バンナ／イギー）えっ！？
the one and only Naruto Uzumaki!
しっかりしろよ。
お前が　ナルトだってばよ。
Shape up!
You are Naruto Uzumaki.
ナルト…。
そうだ！
Naruto...
That's right.
おめえは
天下の英雄　うずまきナルトだ！
You're the hero of justice!
Naruto Uzumaki!
うずまきナルト
一世一代の大暴れだってばよ！
Naruto Uzumaki is going to
go on a rampage of a lifetime!
ひ～っ！
（影たち）うわ～！
（バンナ）うずまきナルトの名前は
返上するよ。
You can have your name back,
Naruto Uzumaki.
俺には荷が重すぎだ。
ありがとう　ナルト。
The weight of it is too heavy to bear.
Thank you, Naruto.
いいってばよ。
Don't mention it.
それより　お前ら
これから　どうするんだ？
But what'll you do from now?
本当に忍者になるつもりか？
いや　やめとくよ。
Do you really intend
to become ninja?
Nah, I'm going to forget about it.
こんな怖え思いするなら
俺には向いてねえ。
If this is how scary it is,
it's not for me.
俺たちは
故郷で地道に暮らすぜ。
I'm going back to the country
and make an honest living.
俺は　イギーが行くなら
どこだっていいぜ。
I'll go wherever Iggy goes.
そうか。
I see.
いつまでも仲よく暮らせよ！
Stay best friends forever, guys!
（イギー）ナルト！
– Naruto!
ありがとよ～！
気をつけてな～！
Thank you!
Take care!
あいつら　でっけえ声で…。
Those guys sure can yell.
達者で暮らせよ～！
Take good care of yourselves!
ヘヘ…　やっぱ親友っていいな。
Best friends are the greatest.
《俺たちも
いつか　あいつらみてえに…》
We'll be like them too, someday.
fight!!
furishiboru dake sa saigo no itteki mo
I'm going to squeeze it down to the last drop
muda ni dekinaikara now is the time to go
Because I can't waste any of it, Now is the time to go
ikudo tsuma tsukimi to egaita yume wa
The dream that I created many times with you
ima koe kuma atte munune o sasu
I can now put it to words and it pierces my heart
it's not crazy
fight and fight, try and try for you
forever
kimi wa hitori janai
You are not alone
namida koete
Get over the tears
kimi to susunde ikou
I'll keep moving forward with you
nani mo kowaku narute na ii na
I'm not afraid of anything
this is the place to try
soshite bokura kitto tsunaida te o
I'm sure we'll never let go
kesshite hanasanaide asu e kakeru
Of each other's hands as we head for tomorrow
let's sing loudly
we are the one for the future
Next Episode
Sand Jonin Temari, you will accept my challenge!
Huh? What are you talking about?
＜今日から８代目＞
My name is Konohamaru Sarutobi.
Grandson of the Third Hokage, Naruto's favorite student!
＜季節のごはんが
大好きな豆助＞
Naruto's...?
Running away from this challenge will mean that you fear me!
は～い　お待たせ
ごはん　できたわよ
Next on Naruto Shippuden: "Naruto's Favorite Student"
Naruto's Favorite Student
This should be fun. I'll indulge you for a little bit.
＜　それは海と大地の恵みが
互いの魅力を最大限に→